I normally do a Christmas recipe today
is no different going to make
gingerbread cookies and
[Music]
cream so yeah I've done Christmas
recipes every year on the channel
whether that
be uh Christmas pudding ice cream back
in the UK that was delicious the first
one was better actually than the second
one but that was store-bought Christmas
puddings and over here
the this is how much they cost and this
is
in two places actually this one one was
a spruce Meadows Christmas Market which
is an excellent Christmas Market in C
actually the best Christmas Market in
Southern Alberta and a second one was at
a British food store great little store
for odds and sods that you can't get
over here but I'm not paying that much
money for a Christmas PUD so it's going
to be gingerbread but this is what you
will need in here we have 4.5 G of
baking soda 8 G of ground cinnamon 5 G
of ground ginger 1 G of ground cloves
and 3 G of pink Himalayan salt in here
we have 165 G of dark brown sugar 170 G
of room temperature butter cut into
pieces
252 G of fancy molasses as it's called
here but it's just dark molasses and
finally 30 G of milk and here here in
our Stam mixer we already have 375 G of
allpurpose flour this it smells great
let's just get on a make so into our
flour we're going to add all our spices
and our salt we're going to add our
sugar and we're going to put this
balloon Whisk on and get
it just mixed together with our dry
ingredients mixed together any lumps of
the sugar will have come out and now
it's time to put our butter in so we're
going to start adding this and just get
it mixed together on low speed until it
crumbles together to make a fine sand or
meie kind of
texture and with that now done the last
stage just to add our molasses and our
milk in here slowly until it all comes
together to create a
dough and now it is an incredibly sticky
dough so we need to get this into the
fridge we're going to get everything off
this balloon whisk and then what we're
going to do is we're going to get it on
some plastic wrap cling film kitchen
foil whatever you want to wrap it in is
fine going to take half the dough and
wrap that
up all recipes tell you to roll it into
a bowl that's a bit silly really cuz you
you're then going to generate Heat by
Rolling it flat so let's tap it
down so that we don't have to generate
any more heat then we absolutely need
to going to fold that over like
that you know exactly the same
again we're going to put both of those
in the refrigerator for at least 24
hours if you don't want to wait that
long you can put it in the freezer for
about half an hour to 45 minutes and
that will harden the dough up enough for
you to work anyway I shall see you on
Thursday our gingerbread cookie dough
has been in the fridge for 2 days what
we're going to do is we're going to get
the dough out we've got our oven
preheating to 350 F which is what 1880
CRA we're going to take one half of our
gingerbread cookie dough out and cut
them up but before we do that because
this is such a soft dough we want to
prepare everything ahead so we're going
to get our baking pans out get some
baking parchment on top um we're going
to do two baking pans because I don't
know how many cookies this is going to
make let's prepare so so I'll cut to
when I've done that flour rolling pin
gingerbread dough going to put some
flour down on the top like I said this
is super super sticky you can actually
just buy gingerbread premix packets in
the supermarket I literally just saw it
in Sao this
morning smells good little bit flour of
the top little bit on the rolling pin
and let's roll this out the more sugar
the softer your gingerbread will be so
we're going to start cutting out our
shapes don't bother trying to pick them
up in individually cuz it's too sticky
shapes are cut out let's remove the
excess dough if they stick just get a
little offset spatula or something and
just gently slide it underneath like
so and we are going to put our
gingerbread
shapes on our baking
sheet it's too sticky to roll out again
without too much flour so I'm going to
probably going to put that in the
freezer and I can use that in the next
few weeks I don't need the other one
because this is a ninja cre
video so I'm going to make a little bit
of room on here get these last two on
there we go we're only going to use one
pan wait until the oven's up to
temperature they're going to go in like
I said or it's basically there 350 F 180
CRA for exactly 10 minutes if you
undercook these they're going to be too
soft if you overcook these they're going
to go too hard and burn so we kind of
want that somewhere in between we want
just enough chew so they keep their
shape don't go super hard in our ice
cream base so 3 2
[Music]
1 right in they go 10 minutes
exactly quick tidy up see you in a
minute we're doing chocolate ice cream
with a little bit of ginger in there so
it's a chocolate Ginger ice cream with
gingerbread cookie
this recipe is for 1 kilo so that's two
standard ninja creamy tubs let's get all
the ingredients out on the top we're
going to use guag gum or gu Gum as some
people moan at me for not saying in
England we would say Gua gum in I think
North America as a whole you say gu gum
it's a cold process stabilizer we're
going to do something with this
chocolate make it a little bit quicker
we're going to take our milk which is
370 g into that we're going to add our
cocoa powder 40 G North America this
apart from valona which actually I think
this is comparable to give or take I
think valona is still a little bit
better than giradelli but giradelli is
North America's second best cocoa powder
we are also going to add in our sugar
165 G and this is brown sugar start to
stir that together we want to try and
get that cocoa powder
submerged under the surface so we need
to break that surface tension caused by
the cocoa
powder cocoa powder does not like to
absorb water until it comes up to a
certain temperature generally around 50
to 55 Centigrade but you can force it by
continually stirring like that we're
doing this because we're going to pop
this in the microwave let's pop this in
the microwave for probably a minute
until it warms up the last of our
ingredients which is 390 G of 33%
whipping cream 35 G of skin milk powder
3/4 of a teaspoon of ground ginger check
on the
mix perfect going to give it another 30
seconds and we're finally going to put
in 1 G of guar gum I spent a lot of time
in the west country so when people say I
should say gu gum makes me sound like a
pirate let's use gu gum there is that
there is
that cookies are done throw that on the
floor we are now just going to stir
these ingredients together the GU gum
sitting on top of the milk powder stir
it together just before you mix it
together gu gum you got me bloody saying
it now gu gum is quite easy to uh
dissipate in liquid much easier than
others and in we're going to pour our
chocolate liquor cream the cold cream
has instantly cooled down our base make
sure that's really combined making a
mess who cares let's get some in our
ninja creamy Tob
in the freezer 6 to 7 hours something
like that come back once that's done all
right we're completely
Frozen it's like it's Monday now so it's
been frozen for 3 days I often get asked
by people to say what setting I spin the
ice creams and gelates on your ice cream
and gelat setting does exactly the same
thing so I wouldn't stress about it it's
just sales pitch
[Music]
you can take one of your gingerbread
cookies break it up into pieces like
that remember these are chewy
gingerbreads meant to be like that put
this back
in run the mix in stage
[Music]
technically this isn't cookers and cream
because there's no cream to these but
you know you get the idea Ginger
chocolate ice cream gingerbread cookies
if you want to add more then after
you've done your spin break off some of
your pieces and just fold them in then
you got really big chunks of gingerbread
let's take a proper spoonful
yes super
nice that Ginger undertone to the
chocolate ice cream it's perfect sets
off with a tiny little bit of
spiciness really really good the
gingerbread
itself is delicious just enough spices
in there to make it really pop without
being overpowering by any one particular
this is a chewy gingerbread
recipe so you you you can you know
whatever but the actual cookies are
delicious if you don't want it as chewy
remove some of the Molasses until you
get to the stage that you want you can
actually just cook these a little bit
longer the perfect cooking time for
these is 10 minutes on the
dot if you cook them for 11 11 and 1/2
minutes just make sure to keep an eye so
they don't burn but you will then dry
out some more of that moisture during
the cooking phase and they won't be as
chewy so kind of balance the recipe to
suit your requirement but this is
incredibly good this is a new Christmas
ice cream whoever you make this for is
going to be super super
happy oh
gone nice bit of ginger in the
background thanks very much for watching
I hope you all have a good festive
season Merry Christmas to those that
celebrate it we certainly do in this
house I'm going to do a yearly catchup
video cuz A lot's happened this
year not just on the channel but in life
um so I'm going to do a yearly catch up
and I'm going to do a Q&A I'm going to
put a post on YouTube and on patreon
send in your questions I will answer as
many as I can in the video don't forget
to like And subscribe see you next time
[Music]